Aditya Sharma

8619766638 | adityashrm91@gmail.com | Jaipur, Rajasthan

Summary

I am a MERN stack developer with over 3 years of experience. I have extensive knowledge of MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, and MicrosoftbotFromework. have worked on several projects that involved designing and developing user interfaces, building RESTful APIs, and integrating third-party services.

Experience

Associate | 01/2021 - 01/2024 | Celebal Technologies | Jaipur, Rajasthan

- Worked on the entire CRM system in Chatbot and Dashboard for India's one of the largest automobile manufacturing company using MERN stack.
- Developed ITSM system in Chatbot and Dashboard in MS Teams for India's largest private sector banks.
- Good experience in NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, MongoDB, and Microsoft Bot Framework.
- Created a dashboard using ReactJS in TypeScript.
- Proficient in using Mongoose, Sequelize, and Prisma ORMs for best backend practices.

Backend Developer | 07/2020 - 09/2020 | Qditch | Jaipur, Rajasthan

- Freelancing project built from scratch in Python (Django). This website allows users to book the salon's stylist online.
- · Integrated Booking management system.
- Skilled in allowing users to choose their favorite saloon and stylist and cancel the reservation.
- Gave authority to a stylist to cancel the booking of the user.

Backend Developer Intern | 01/2020 - 05/2020 | Homy Bee | Jaipur, Rajasthan

- Responsible for developing the whole backend of the E-Commerce startup from scratch.
- Used the following technologies in the process: Django (Python), Redis (Caching & NoSQL database),
 WebSockets (asynchronous chat events), ElasticSearch (Search-Engine), AWS (EC2, S3 Bucket, SNS, SES), Pytest (Unit-Testing), JWT-Token Authentication, PostgreSQL (Database) etc.

Skills

JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Python, MySQL, JQuery, HTML 5, CSS, Django, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git

Education

B.Tech | Rajasthan Technical University | 08/2021 | Jaipur, Rajasthan

Object-Oriented Design, Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management System, Operating System, and Software Engineering.

Languages

English, Hindi

Personal Projects

InfluBot

- Users can interact with the creator's bot and ask the bot to connect with the creator via chatting, audio call or video call
- Implementation of Agora service for Audio/Video call